{"version": "1.1.0", "data": "New offensive against Taliban in Orūzgān\n\nThe Dutch army started, in co-operation with U.S. and Afghan soldiers a new offensive against the Taliban in the Orūzgān province of Afghanistan. The Dutch hope to secure safety and security in the area of Deh Rawood, says a spokesman of the Dutch ministry of Defence. Enemy troops have gained strength in the area. \"Because of this, the rebuilding was slowed down, and the local population were under bigger pressure,\" the spokesman says. \n\nWomen think about sex too\n\nWomen think about sex just as often as men, says British dating-site \"Dating Direct\". Common perception is that men are more occupied with sex than women, but women think about sex 34 times a day, which is every 14th minute. \n\nDating Direct performed a survey on 1,000 women asking, questions about their sexlife. Almost 50% of them are not satisfied, making them think of sex more, especially when they are at work. \n\nHeavy snow in Greece and Turkey\n\nSouthern Greece and large parts of Turkey were hit by heavy snowfall today. Greek capital Athens was covered by a 20 cm layer of snow on Monday morning, causing major traffic problems. In some areas, the snow blanket was as thick as 50 cm. The capital's airport has been closed.\n", "attributes": {"entities": {"type": "list", "itemType": "entities", "items": [{"mentions": [{"startOffset": 22, "endOffset": 29}], "type": "ORG", "entityId": "Q42418"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 33, "endOffset": 40}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q183028"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 46, "endOffset": 51}], "type": "NAT", "entityId": "Q200569"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 87, "endOffset": 91}], "type": "NAT", "entityId": "Q846570"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 96, "endOffset": 102}], "type": "NAT", "entityId": "Q16007968"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 140, "endOffset": 147}], "type": "ORG", "entityId": "Q42418"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 155, "endOffset": 162}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q183028"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 175, "endOffset": 186}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q889"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 192, "endOffset": 197}], "type": "NAT", "entityId": "Q200569"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 248, "endOffset": 258}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q2342330"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 284, "endOffset": 309}], "type": "ORG", "entityId": "Q2119820"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 560, "endOffset": 567}], "type": "NAT", "entityId": "Q842438"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 944, "endOffset": 950}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q41"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 955, "endOffset": 961}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q43"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 972, "endOffset": 978}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q41"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 998, "endOffset": 1004}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q43"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 1039, "endOffset": 1052}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q1524"}, {"mentions": [{"startOffset": 1053, "endOffset": 1059}], "type": "LOC", "entityId": "Q1524"}]}}, "documentMetadata": {"title": ["Wikinews Shorts: February 18, 2008"], "language": ["en"], "direction": ["ltr"], "published_date": ["2008-02-18"], "accessed_date": ["2020-08-19T17:00:45.268434"], "url": ["https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Wikinews_Shorts:_February_18,_2008"], "domain": ["https://en.wikinews.org"], "wikinews_categories": ["https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Afghanistan", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Archived", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Asia", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Athens,_Greece", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Environment", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Europe", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:February_18,_2008", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Greece", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Health", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Mental_health", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Netherlands", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Politics_and_conflicts", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Published", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Turkey", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:United_Kingdom", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Weather", "https://en.wikinews.org/wiki/Category:Wikinews_Shorts"], "uuid": ["06fc6fe5600134a1a5bba37943f7abb3"], "license": ["https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5/"], "annotators": ["ANN_2", "ANN_1", "ANN_0"], "adjudicators": ["ADJ_0", "ADJ_2"]}}
